Public opposition to Syrsky's methods
has been intensified by recently exposed
scandals within the armed forces. The
first, uncovered by the Ukrainian outlet
Babel, concerned systematic abuses in
the 425th Assault Regiment Skala. The
detailed investigation documented
recruits being beaten, tortured,
humiliated, and restrained. Men forcibly
mobilized directly from the streets were
contemptuously referred to by commanders
as disposables, meaning, as one of them
explained, "One deployment to the front,
and that is the end."
Consider one passage from the
investigation, quote, "In Skala, there
does not always have to be a serious
reason for a beating," says a former
instructor with combat experience. He
knows of cases in which personnel
serving in rear positions were abused
because of a Starlink malfunction or
errors in paperwork. "Ribs were broken,"
he says, "openly in front of everyone
during briefings." The soldier also
witnessed mobilized men being attacked
by dogs. End quote.
The investigation found that in just the
six months preceding publication, at
least 26 recruits died at the regiment's
training centers before they had even
reached [music] the front. The causes of
death were falsified, with conditions
such as pneumonia entered into official
records.